PO-KAI CHANG

+886-939-098-869 pokaichangtwn@gmail.com

Software Engineer with 16 months in delivering and maintaining an in-house DSP (Demand Side Platform) for telecoms and with another 8 months in ML research. Adept to designing and building backend dataflow, performance testing and tuning on backend, and integrating backend techs. Passionate in implementing solutions on Docker, carrying out rapid development on Node.js or Python, and applying ML libraries.

EMPLOYMENT

Software Engineer

Groundhog Technologies

Apr 2016 to Aug 2017

MI DSP

- Delivered and maintained an in-house DSP backend tailored for telecoms.
- Created highly scalable RTB modules through Nodejs with Redis and the logging system: Rsyslog, Kafka, ELK.
- Fulfilled the deployment of the stand-alone MI DSP through docker-compose without network support.
- Strengthened MI DSP to reach at least 5K qps in pressure tests with 5 times throughput improvement.
- Integrated with Exchanges including Google DoubleClick and Smaato through OpenRTB protocol.
- Implemented the data visualization system, ELK, to monitor bidding and provide ML insights.
- Accomplished the collection of user behavior data through embedded codes and Integration with AppsFlyer.
- Mentored two interns and collaborated with two colleagues on the design of backend architect, development, deployment of MI DSP.

Data Scientist

Groundhog Technologies

Jul 2015 to Apr 2016

- Built a user satisfaction indicator from telecom data through LIBSVM.
- Redesigned the existing classification method of the telecom subscribers' home/work locations in RBM and DNN under DL4j.

EDUCATION

National Taiwan University

Sep 2010 to Jun 2015

- B.S.E. in Economics and Mathematics with Minor in Computer Science. Overall GPA: 3.78/4.0
- Undergraduate Coursework: Operating Systems; System Programming; Algorithms; Computer Architecture; Advanced Calculus; Statistics.

SKILLS

- Programming: Node.js (1.5y), Python (1y), Scala, REST, C/C++, Linux Shell (2y), Linux Awk (2y)
- Database: Redis (1.5y), MongoDB, Elasticsearch
- Quality: automation test (Mocha), CI (GitLab), load tests (ApacheBench)
- ML libraries: DL4j, SciPy, scikit-learn, LIBSVM
- Logging and visualization: Kafka cluster, Rsyslog (central log), ELK (Elasticsearch, Logstash, Kibana)
- · API: OpenRTB, DoubleClick Ad Exchange Buyer API, REST
- Others: Docker, Nginx (load balancer), Behavior Tracking (beacon, cookie), Spark Cluster, Big Data Analysis, Unix, Networking, Deep Learning, Vim, Tmux, fearless debugging